<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: From Vietnam | Vietnam Vascular Anomalies Center]]></title>
  <link href="http://vietnamvac.org/blog/categories/from-vietnam/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://vietnamvac.org/"/>
  <updated>2019-11-05T22:07:18-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://vietnamvac.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[VietnamVAC]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vietnamese Hospital Ceases Phosphorus Treatment]]></title>
    <link href="http://vietnamvac.org/blog/2012/09/05/vietnamese-hospital-phosphorus/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://vietnamvac.org/blog/2012/09/05/vietnamese-hospital-phosphorus</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We would like to share with you a great news from Vietnam Vascular Anomalies Center (VAC).   The Cancer Hospital in Ho Chi Minh City will no longer perform radioactive phosphorus 32P treatment for hemangiomas in children!  It is a great achievement for Vietnam VAC, especially for VAC&rsquo;s Medical Director Dr. Hoang Minh and the medical team in Vietnam, who have worked tirelessly to make this happen and have aired our interview when we were in Saigon as well as a documentary about hemangiomas, its current treatments including laser therapy, and the damages done to children from radioactive phosphorus!  The Vietnam television crew was also very helpful, airing the documentary at least 4-5 times to help raise awareness.  The doctors and the Cancer Hospital have admitted that the treatment is harmful and are interested in collaborating with our doctors at VAC to learn about new therapies for hemangiomas and port-wine-stains.</p>

<p>This is fantastic news and one of the primary goals of Vietnam VAC!  We are so grateful for all of your support and hard work to make this happen!  It is a beginning step to get modern treatment to the children with vascular birthmarks in Vietnam.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The New Vascular Anomalies Center in Vietnam]]></title>
    <link href="http://vietnamvac.org/blog/2012/03/28/the-new-vascular-anomalies-center-in-vietnam/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://vietnamvac.org/blog/2012/03/28/the-new-vascular-anomalies-center-in-vietnam</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are very excited to share with you that we are now a formal center at the University of Medicine and Pharmacy of Ho Chi Minh City, a premier training and educational center in Southern Vietnam.  The ribbon cutting ceremony was performed on March 6th, 2012 and the formal ceremony was done in conjunction with our third anniversary and conference at the White Palace on March 8th, 2012.  This is very exciting for us as we now have a permanent home at the University Medical Center, Branch No 3.  This will lead to better, more coordinated patient care as well as enhanced ability for teaching, training, and humanitarian collaboration.</p>

<p>We look forward to sharing with you more news about the Center in the coming months.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Letter From 2012 Vietnam Visit]]></title>
    <link href="http://vietnamvac.org/blog/2012/03/28/letter-from-2012-vietnam-visit/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://vietnamvac.org/blog/2012/03/28/letter-from-2012-vietnam-visit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dear Friends and Colleagues,</p>

<p>We have just returned from Vietnam again on a most exciting trip.  We have happy news to share with you all:  we are now formally designated as part of the University of Medicine and Pharmacy of Ho Chi Minh City as a Center for Vascular Anomalies.  We have a formal and permanent office, operating room and the enthusiastic support of the University Medical Center, Branch No 3.  With this new capacity, we will be able to touch so many more lives and work towards fulfilling the mission of the Vietnam VAC:</p>

<ul>
<li>Continue to provide excellent care for our patients affected by vascular and pigmentary birthmarks</li>
<li>Many other dermatologic problems including vitiligo</li>
<li>Scholarly research that will enhance the understanding and treatment of these lesions</li>
<li>Humanitarian medical collaboration between US and Vietnamese physicians</li>
</ul>


<p>With the generous support of laser devices from Candela/Syneron and Lumenis Corporations, we were able to offer treatment to many children with vascular/pigmented birthmarks as well as disfiguring scars.  Thousands of children remain untreated in underdeveloped nations around the world where access to care as well as correct treatment is often out-of-reach.  The most striking example as been the continued use of radioactive phosphorus 32 in Saigon to treat hemangiomas in children, an outdated procedure that causes severe scarring and depigmentation, not including the risk of malignancy.  We are working hard with our colleagues in Vietnam to try to change this practice and also are working toward a potential treatment to improve the scars in these children.  Our work in Saigon has touched over  700 children thus far – and with your help, we are expanding the reach of our program.
We again would like to extend our heartfelt gratitude for supporting our effort in Vietnam. You are all essential members of our team who have volunteered time, resources, and effort towards this worthwhile cause. Without your support, we would not be able to maintain and expand our clinic.  Thank you again for your generosity.</p>

<p>Here are a few images from our trip. We all had a wonderful time and formed new friendships while working hard in the operating room.  We will also continue to update our website with the latest information about the clinic, including photos, blog, treatment results, future fund raising efforts, etc.
Warm regards,</p>

<p>Rox Anderson, MD<br/>
Stuart Nelson, MD<br/>
Tri Nguyen, MD<br/>
Thuy Phung, MD PhD<br/>
Thanh Nga T. Tran, MD PhD</p>

<p>PS: Please <a href="/media/vietnam-2012/">view the photos</a> from our trip</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Letter From 2011 Vietnam Visit]]></title>
    <link href="http://vietnamvac.org/blog/2011/03/01/letter-from-2011-vietnam-visit/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://vietnamvac.org/blog/2011/03/01/letter-from-2011-vietnam-visit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dear Friends and Colleagues,</p>

<p>We would like to share with you a few images from our recent trip to Vietnam for the second anniversary of the Vietnam Vascular Anomalies Clinic.   With the generous support of laser devices from Candela/Syneron and Lumenis Corporations, we were able to offer treatment to many children with vascular/pigmented birthmarks as well as disfiguring scars.  In addition, we were also able to help train our colleagues in Vietnam in the latest technologies with the hope of providing good care for the children of Vietnam.  Thousands of children remain untreated in underdeveloped nations around the world where access to care as well as correct treatment is often out-of-reach.  The most striking example as been the continued use of radioactive phosphorus 32 in Saigon to treat hemangiomas in children, an outdated procedure that causes severe scarring and depigmentation, not including the risk of malignancy.  We are working hard with our colleagues in Vietnam to try to change this practice.  Our work in Saigon has touched over 500 children thus far – and with your help, we are expanding the reach of our program.</p>

<p>We again would like to extend our heartfelt gratitude for supporting our effort in Vietnam. You are all essential members of our team who have volunteered time, resources, and effort towards this worthwhile cause. Without your support, we would not be able to maintain and expand our clinic.  Thank you again for your generosity.</p>

<p>Here are a few images from our trip. We all had a wonderful time and formed new friendships while working hard in the operating room.  We will also continue to update our website with the latest information about the clinic, including photos, blog, treatment results, future fund raising efforts, etc.</p>

<p>Sincerely,</p>

<p>Thanh-Nga Tran</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
